<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Etcs on Gavaskar blog</title>
    <link>https://gawasinspire.github.io/etc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Etcs on Gavaskar blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://gawasinspire.github.io/etc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://gawasinspire.github.io/etc/gavaskar-kanagaraj-191f4add676b42ac9d1d6dffc1d6e84e/learning-journals-c2eccd8b45e348ef9b7f491b420d2322/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gawasinspire.github.io/etc/gavaskar-kanagaraj-191f4add676b42ac9d1d6dffc1d6e84e/learning-journals-c2eccd8b45e348ef9b7f491b420d2322/</guid>
      <description>Learning Journals I am passionate about Embedded stuffs.
Day 1:
Total chaos&amp;hellip;
they introduced 42 concepts and tribe concepts. Also notion and suggested to profile our self : ended in chaos, as instructed students started to copy/clone, edit the profile from everyone. The profile owners got frustrated and started to freaking out. After some meetings, it was regulated. There is a gamification concept through which we get points for community meetings, peer meeting, for being online in discord.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://gawasinspire.github.io/etc/gavaskar-kanagaraj-191f4add676b42ac9d1d6dffc1d6e84e/my-goals-okrs-040273f440b64d01a946cfe785dd559e/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gawasinspire.github.io/etc/gavaskar-kanagaraj-191f4add676b42ac9d1d6dffc1d6e84e/my-goals-okrs-040273f440b64d01a946cfe785dd559e/</guid>
      <description>My Goals &amp;amp; OKRs On this page you can reflect in more detail on your personal learning goals and specify OKRs to make sure you can track your progress.
Remember that you can use the SKATE Competence model and the Bloom Taxonomy to increase the variety of goals and choose explicit language so others and your future your don&amp;rsquo;t misunderstand what you want to achieve.
You can also invite people to give you feedback on your goals or create small groups to do timed check-ins to talk about your goals and your progress.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://gawasinspire.github.io/etc/gavaskar-kanagaraj-191f4add676b42ac9d1d6dffc1d6e84e/who-what-why-983420840b9c4607872418cf79a2d3e1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gawasinspire.github.io/etc/gavaskar-kanagaraj-191f4add676b42ac9d1d6dffc1d6e84e/who-what-why-983420840b9c4607872418cf79a2d3e1/</guid>
      <description>Who, What, Why Pisciner
🎯 Learning Goals: What do I want to learn?  Embedded Development Linux Kernel Development  🦸‍♀️ Motivation: Why do I want to learn that?  From the childhood, i am fascinated to make things to move. This curiosity landed up in embedded where i could hardcore stuffs to behave or imitate like lively beings. I believe this kind of technologies (which are already playing a prominent) but also will play vital role in near futures.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
